Guide to the Wendell Holmes Stephenson Papers, 1820-1968
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Wendell Holmes Stephenson papers 1820-1968
Stephenson, Wendell Holmes, 1899-1970
34.6 linear feet Extent: circa 25,950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Durham, North Carolina 27708-0185
RL.01249
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers of Wendell Holmes Stephenson (1893-1970), historian, university professor, and editor, were donated to the Special Collections Department in 1963 and 1972 by Dr. and Mrs. Wendell Holmes Stephenson.
Biographical Note
1899, March 13 Born, Cartersville, Indiana
1917-1921 Teacher in public schools of Indiana
1923 A.B., Indiana University
1924 A.M., Indiana University
1924-1926 Instructor and assistant professor of history and political science, University of Kentucky
1927-1945 Associate professor and professor of American history, Louisiana State University
1928 Ph.D., University of Michigan
1935-1941 Editor, Journal of Southern History
1940-1941 President, Agricultural History Society
1941-1944 Dean, College of Arts and Sciences, Louisiana State University
1944 President, Southern Historical Association
1946-1953 Managing editor, Mississippi Valley Historical Review Professor of Southern history and chairman, Division of Social Sciences, Tulane University
1953-1970 Professor of history, University of Oregon
1957-1958 President, Mississippi Valley Historical Association
1970, April 14 Died, Eugene, Oregon
Collection Overview
The papers of Wendell Holmes Stephenson span the years 1820-1968, but the bulk of the materials date from 1922 to 1968. They consist of correspondence, writings and speeches, research and teaching material, and subject files. The collection primarily concerns Stephenson's career as a university professor, historian and author, and editor of historical journals. His field was Southern history but included American history, and his interests spanned the colonial period to the 20th century.
The beginnings of Stephenson's career are documented in a limited number of letters, writings, and notes dating from his undergraduate studies at Indiana University and his graduate work at the University of Michigan in the 1920s. These materials are scattered principally in the Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, and Teaching Materials series.
The materials about his career as teacher, editor, and historical writer from the 1920s to the 1960s are not neatly segregated into particular series. The Journal of Southern History Series does record the bulk of his work with that publication, but information about particular persons, topics, and institutions is often available in more than one series, sometimes in all of them.
The Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, Subject Files, Teaching Material, and Research and Bibliographical Notes series span Stephenson's career from the 1920s to the 1960s. The Correspondence Series is considerably more extensive than the other series. Information about individuals, schools, associations, and publishers is principally filed in the Correspondence, Writings and Speeches, Subject Files, and Teaching Material series. The Research and Bibliographical Notes series contains Stephenson's research notes about persons, places, and topics in Southern and American history, but additional notes and information about them may also appear in other series.
Stephenson was the first editor of the Journal of Southern History that began publication in 1935. Correspondence files are extensive, and some subject files are also available. The papers document the operations of the Journal during Stephenson's editorship, 1935-1941, but also to a limited extent as late as 1944 and in the years prior to the inception of publication. The activity recorded ranges from routine business to dealings with the principal scholars in the field. What Southern history was during this period and who was doing research and writing is amply documented.
Stephenson was later the editor of another important journal, the Mississippi Valley Historical Review, during 1946-1953. Files under its name are in the Correspondence and Subject Files series. However, there are many more files in the Correspondence Series because he integrated his editorial files into his other correspondence. Material about the Review is not confined to the years of Stephenson's editorship.
Manuscripts of the articles and books of various historians are sometimes included in their files in the Journal of Southern History, Subject Files, and Correspondence series. In most cases the presence of these writings is related to Stephenson's editorial work, but some were filed because he was interested in the work of earlier historians.
Subject Headings
Louisiana State University -- Faculty; Southern Historical Association -- History; Tulane University -- Faculty; University of Kentucky -- Faculty; University of Oregon -- Faculty; Journal of Southern History; Mississippi Valley Historical Review; College teachers as authors; Historians -- Societies, etc.; Historians -- Southern States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Historiography -- United States; College teaching; Scholarly publishing; Southern States -- History; United States -- History; History -- Societies, etc.
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1921-1968
  Primarily correspondence related to Stephenson's teaching, research, and editorial work including files for individuals, institutions, associations, publishers, and topics. Arranged chronologically.
  - A-K
    - Selective List of References to Persons, and Schools, and Mississippi Valley Historical Association (Box 1)
    - Ac-As, 1944-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Abbott, W. W., 1955-1962 (Box 1)
    - Abernethy, Thomas, P., 1945-1961, undated (Box 1)
    - Abramowitz, Jack, 1947-1950 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Mary, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Administrative Services, 1949, undated (Box 1)
    - Affleck, T. D., 1935-1955 (Box 1)
    - Affleck, Thomas: Papers, 1953-1954, undated (Box 1)
    - Agnew, Dwight L., 1946-1958, undated (Box 1)
    - Agnew, Theodore L., 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Agricultural History Society, 1941-1960, undated (Box 1)
    - Aiton, Arthur S., 1946-1947 (Box 1)
    - Alden, John R., 1946-1964, undated (Box 1)
    - Alderson, William T., 1952 (Box 1)
    - Alef, Gus, 1957-1962, undated (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Arthur J., 1949 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Edward P., 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - Alilunas, Leo J., 1946-1949 (Box 1)
    - Aly, Bower, 1948-1958 (Box 1)
    - American Book Company, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    - American Historical Association, 1941-1956, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - American History Research Center, 1951-1957, undated (Box 2)
    - Ander, O. Fritiof, 1948-1950 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Arlow W., 1947 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Francis Fern, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, George L., 1951-1956 (Box 2)
    - Anderson, Russell H., 1946-1954 (Box 2)
    - Andreasson, Dagny, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Andreasson, John C. L., 1946-1951 (Box 2)
    - Andrew, Bunyan H., 1949 (Box 2)
    - Angle, Paul M., 1947-1952 (Box 2)
    - Arrington, J. Earl, 1952-1953, undated (Box 2)
    - Athearn, Robert G., 1948-1952, undated (Box 2)
    - Atherton, Lewis E., 1947-1957, undated (Box 2)
    - Atkinson, Boone, 1946-1953, undated (Box 2)
    - Auer, J. Jeffrey, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Austin, Lucy E., 1955, undated88 (Box 2)
    - Austin, Ward H., 1956 (Box 2)
    - Ba-Bu and Misc. B, 1930-1966, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - Babb, James T., 1949 (Box 2)
    - Babin, Claude G., 1946-1954 (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Thomas A., 1946-1958 (Box 2)
    - Bailkey, Nels M., 1947-1952 (Box 2)
    - Banta, R. E., 1949-1950, undated (Box 2)
    - Barbee, David R., 1948 (Box 2)
    - Barber, Hollis, 1946-1958, undated (Box 2)
    - Barker, Burt Brown, 1956-1959, undated (Box 2)
    - Barker, Charles A., 1949-1959 (Box 2)
    - Barker, E. C., 1942-1949, undated (Box 3)
    - Barnes, James A., 1947-1958, undated (Box 3)
    - Barnhardt, John D., 1944-1957, undated (Box 3)
    - Barry, J. Neilson, 1949-1959, undated (Box 3)
    - Barth, Gunther, 1955-1968, undated (Box 3)
    - Bauman, Harold, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
    - Beale, Howard K., 1944-1953 (Box 3)
    - Beck, Earl R., 1948-1952 (Box 3)
    - Bedsole, Virgil L., 1949 1954 (Box 3)
    - Beers, Henry P., 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Betts, John, 1949-1962, undated (Box 3)
    - Beveridge, Albert J., Memorial Fellowship, 1947-1951 (Box 3)
    - Bestor, Arthur E., Jr., 1950-1953 (Box 3)
    - Bezanson, Warren B., 1947-1948 (Box 3)
    - Bieber, Ralph, 1947-1955 (Box 3)
    - Biel, John G., 1949-1951 (Box 3)
    - Biester, Charlotte, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Billington, Ray A., 1947-1963, undated (Box 3)
    - Billman, C. J., 1954-1961 (Box 3)
    - Binsfords and Mort, Publishers, 1950, undated (Box 3)
    - Bingham, Harold J., 1947-1956, undated (Box 3)
    - Binkley, William C., 1943-1948 (Box 3)
    - Binkley, William C., 1949-1962 (Box 4)
    - Blackenburg, Howard, 1945, undated (Box 4)
    - Blake, I. George, 1944-1958 (Box 4)
    - Blegen, Theodore C., 1948-1951 (Box 4)
    - Blickensderfer, Joseph P., 1945-1953, undated (Box 4)
    - Bobbs Merrill Co., 1930-1952 (Box 4)
    - Boggs, Hale, 1948-1951 (Box 4)
    - Bonner, James C., 1947-1950 (Box 4)
    - Bonner, Thomas N., 1949-1952 (Box 4)
    - Bonnett, Clarence E., 1949 (Box 4)
    - Bornet, Vaughn D., 1951-1955 (Box 4)
    - Borth, Daniel, 1949 (Box 4)
    - Bowsky, William, 1957-1965, undated (Box 4)
    - Boyce, G. C., 1948-1952 (Box 4)
    - Boyd, William B., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Bradley, Howard W., 1946-1961 (Box 4)
    - Brayer, Herbert O., 1946-1949, undated (Box 4)
    - Brebner, J. Bartlet, 1947-1948 (Box 4)
    - Bremner, R. H., 1950 (Box 4)
    - Bridenbaugh, Carl, 1947-1953 (Box 4)
    - Briggs, Harold E., 1946-1955, undated (Box 4)
    - Brockman, Charles, Jr., 1952, undated (Box 4)
    - Brokaw, R. Mariam, 1955-1956, undated (Box 4)
    - Brooks, Edward Howard, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Brown, Ira Vernon, 1951-1952, undated (Box 4)
    - Brown, R. B., 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Brown, Richard C., 1952, undated (Box 4)
    - Brown, Sydney M., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Brown, W. Burlie, 1949-1962, undated (Box 5)
    - Burr, C. Brundage, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Bryan, T. Conn, 1946-1960, undated (Box 5)
    - Bryan, William A., 1948 (Box 5)
    - Brydon, Ellen Page, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Buchan, L. J., 1947-1949 (Box 5)
    - Buchanan, A. Russell, 1948-1952 (Box 5)
    - Buck, Martina E., 1949-1951, undated (Box 5)
    - Buck, Solon J., 1948-1952 (Box 5)
    - Buley, R. C., 1946-1951 (Box 5)
    - Burns, R. Ignatius, S. J., 1950-1951 (Box 5)
    - Business Historical Society, 1952, undated (Box 5)
    - Ca-Cu, 1921-1962, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Caldwell, Norman W., 1948-1952 (Box 5)
    - Callahan, North, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Callcott, Wildred H., 1945-1952 (Box 5)
    - Campbell, C. H., 1947-1953 (Box 5)
    - Cannon, Mary, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Capers, Gerald, 1947-1951 (Box 5)
    - Cappon, Lester J., 1944-1952 (Box 5)
    - Carbone, George A., 1948 (Box 5)
    - Carmony, Donald F., 1958-1959 (Box 5)
    - Carpenter, Hazen C., 1950, undated (Box 5)
    - Carriere, J. M., 1948-1949 (Box 5)
    - Carroll, H. Bailey, 1948-1952 (Box 5)
    - Carson, George, 1948-1958 (Box 5)
    - Carter, Harvey L., 1947-1957 (Box 5)
    - Case, Lynn M., 1943-1952, undated (Box 5)
    - Cate, James Lea, 1947, undated (Box 5)
    - Catton, Bruce, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Caughey, John, 1946-1961, undated (Box 6)
    - Caxton Printers, Ltd., 1947-1950 (Box 6)
    - Centennial Lectures Committee, 1958 (Box 6)
    - Chandler, L. E., 1946 (Box 6)
    - Cheatham, Edgar J., Jr., 1949-1961 (Box 6)
    - Cherry, George L., 1949 (Box 6)
    - Chessman, G. Wallace, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
    - Chitty, Arthur B., Jr., 1951-1965, undated (Box 6)
    - Chitwood, O. P., 1948-1952 (Box 6)
    - Christenson, T. P., 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    - Clark, Arthur H., Publishing Company, 1949-1951, undated (Box 6)
    - Clark, R. T. Rundle, 1950-1951, undated (Box 6)
    - Clark, Robert D., 1947-1962 (Box 6)
    - Clark, Thomas D., 1944-1962, undated (Box 6)
    - Clinch, Thomas A., 1958-1967, undated (Box 6)
    - Clodius, Albert H., 1950 (Box 6)
    - Clough, Shepard, 1949 (Box 6)
    - Clyde, Paul H., 1946-1954, undated (Box 6)
    - Cochran, Thomas C., 1946-1949 (Box 6)
    - Coddington, E. B., 1947-1960, undated (Box 6)
    - Coffee, James M., 1950 (Box 6)
    - Cogan, Felicia Lee, 1957-1962 (Box 6)
    - Cole, Charles C., Jr., 1948-1949 (Box 6)
    - Cole, Fred C., 1941-1953, undated (Box 7)
    - Cole, Wayne S., 1949-1952 (Box 7)
    - Coleman, J. Winston, Jr., 1945-1958 (Box 7)
    - Coletta, Paolo E., 1952 (Box 7)
    - Comeau, James L., 1952 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Middle-American Studies, 1947-1948 (Box 7)
    - Corbitt, D. L., 1947-1948, undated (Box 7)
    - Cotner, Robert C., 1947, undated (Box 7)
    - Cotterill, R. S., 1946-1955, undated (Box 7)
    - Council for Basic Education, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
    - Coulter, E. Merton, 1942-1967, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Cox, Isaac Joslin, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
    - Craig, Charles R., 1946-1950 (Box 7)
    - Crane, Verner W., 1945-1958 (Box 7)
    - Craven, Avery O., 1943-1960, undated (Box 7)
    - Craven, W. F., 1946-1949, undated (Box 7)
    - Crittendon, C. C., 1943-1947, undated (Box 7)
    - Culver, Thelma B., 1954 (Box 7)
    - Current, Richard N., 1946-1953 (Box 7)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1947-1952, undated (Box 8)
    - Curti, Merle, 1947-1959, undated (Box 8)
    - Da-Dy, 1931-1962, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - D. C. Heath and Company, 1947-1948 (Box 8)
    - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1947-1961, undated (Box 8)
    - Dale, E. E., 1947-1952, undated (Box 8)
    - Dater, Henry M., 1947-1948 (Box 8)
    - Davenport, Garvin, 1948-1950 (Box 8)
    - Davidson, Philip, 1942-1953, undated (Box 8)
    - Davies, Wallace E., 1946-1948, undated (Box 8)
    - Davis, Curtis Carroll, 1951 (Box 8)
    - Davis, Edwin A., 1935-1961, undated (Box 8)
    - Davis, Elmer O., 1951, undated (Box 8)
    - Davis, Granville D., 1949-1952, undated (Box 8)
    - Davis, J. Treadwell, 1950-1951 (Box 8)
    - Davis, William N., 1949 (Box 8)
    - Debien, Gabriel, 1943 (Box 8)
    - Deconde, Alexander, 1952 (Box 8)
    - Degler, Carl N., 1952-1953 (Box 8)
    - Denbo, Bruce, 1947-1957 (Box 8)
    - De Novo, John G. (Box 8)
    - Denoyer-Geppert Co., 1945-1947, undated (Box 8)
    - Destler, Chester McArthur, 1946-1953, undated (Box 9)
    - Detweiler, Philip F., 1956-1964 (Box 9)
    - De Weerd, H. A., 1947-1949 (Box 9)
    - Dick, Everett, 1947-1950 (Box 9)
    - Dickerson, O. M., 1948-1952 (Box 9)
    - Dickey, Dallas C., 1944-1955 (Box 9)
    - Diket, Albert L., 1953-1959, undated (Box 9)
    - Diller, Aubrey, 1948-1949 (Box 9)
    - Dillon, Richard H., 1950-1951, undated (Box 9)
    - Dimick, Howard T., 1947-1948 (Box 9)
    - Donald, David, 1948-1960 (Box 9)
    - Donnan, Elizabeth, 1948, undated (Box 9)
    - Dorris, J. T., 1946-1950 (Box 9)
    - Dowd, D. L., 1948-1949 (Box 9)
    - Dozer, Donald Marquand, 1944-1949, undated (Box 9)
    - Dudley, D. R., 1950-1953, undated (Box 9)
    - Duffy, Charles, 1947 (Box 9)
    - Dufour, Charles L., 1952, undated (Box 9)
    - Duke University, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Dumond, Dwight L., 1946-1958 (Box 9)
    - Duncan, Donald, 1960-1962, undated (Box 9)
    - Dunham, William H., Jr., 1951-1952, undated (Box 9)
    - Dusenberry, William H., 1948 (Box 9)
    - Dyer, Brainerd, 1944-1958 (Box 9)
    - Dyer, John P., 1948-1952, undated (Box 9)
    - Ea-Ex, 1928-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Earle, T. T., 1947-1953, undated (Box 10)
    - East, Robert A., 1947-1952 (Box 10)
    - Easterby, J. H., 1947-1951 (Box 10)
    - Easum, C. V., 1951-1952 (Box 10)
    - Eaton, Clement, 1942-1961, undated (Box 10)
    - Educational Policy Committee, 1946-1948, undated (Box 10)
    - Edwards, Everett E., 1941-1951 (Box 10)
    - Edwards, Tom, 1959-1967, undated (Box 10)
    - Ellickson, R. T., 1954-1958 (Box 10)
    - Ellis, Elmer, 1946-1953, undated (Box 10)
    - Ellison, Simon, J., 1952-1953 (Box 10)
    - England, Merton, 1943-1957 (Box 10)
    - English, W. Francis, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Esterline, John H., 1951 (Box 10)
    - Euhul, Magdalen, 1950 (Box 10)
    - European Tour, 1950-1951, undated (Box 10)
    - Everette, Donald E., 1950-1962, undated (Box 10)
    - Ewing, Russ, 1947 (Box 10)
    - Exchanges of Historical Quarterlies with the Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1946-1951, undated (Box 10)
    - Extension Courses, L.S.U., 1940-1941, undated (Box 10)
    - Extension Division, L.S.U., 1939-1941 (Box 10)
    - Ezell, John S., 1950 (Box 10)
    - Fa-Fu, 1929-1961, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Faculty-Constitution, 1939, undated (Box 11)
    - Faines, Oscar, 1947 (Box 11)
    - Fanton, Conrad R., 1949 (Box 11)
    - Fechter, Clay, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
    - Fehrenbacher, Don E., 1951-1955, undated (Box 11)
    - Ferguson, Arthur B., 1948 (Box 11)
    - Ferguson, James S., 1946-1967 (Box 11)
    - Ferguson, R. J., 1927-1953, undated (Box 11)
    - Fifield, Russell H., 1952-1953 (Box 11)
    - Filson Club, 1946-1947, undated (Box 11)
    - Fine, Sidney, 1950-1951, undated (Box 11)
    - Finkenberg, Edward, 1952-1953 (Box 11)
    - Fiore, Jordan D., 1952 (Box 11)
    - Fischer, LeRoy H., 1948-1954, undated (Box 11)
    - Fishwick, Marshall W., 1951-1952 (Box 11)
    - Fite, Gilbert C., 1947-1958, undated (Box 11)
    - Flanders, B. F. Collection, 1942 (Box 11)
    - Fleming Lectures, 1937-1956 (Box 11)
    - Flemming, Arthur, 1963-1967, undated (Box 11)
    - Folmsbee, S. J., 1947-1948 (Box 11)
    - Forbes, Gerald, 1947-1949 (Box 11)
    - Ford, Edwin H., 1948-1953 (Box 11)
    - Ford, Guy Stanton, 1946-1952 (Box 11)
    - Foreman, Grant, 1950 (Box 11)
    - Forest History Foundation, Inc., 1955-1961, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Fornell, Earl W., 1950-1951 (Box 12)
    - Foster, James W., 1946-1947 (Box 12)
    - Franklin, John Hope, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Frantz, Joe B., 1948-1961 (Box 12)
    - Fries, Robert F., 1947-1950 (Box 12)
    - Froom, L. E., 1951-1952, undated (Box 12)
    - Fulbright Act, 1949-1950, undated (Box 12)
    - Funkhouser, W. D., 1945-1946, undated (Box 12)
    - Ga-Gu and Misc. G., 1946-1965, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Gafford, Frank H., 1949-1952 (Box 12)
    - Gaines, William, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Galbraith, John S., 1948-1953, undated (Box 12)
    - Gambrell, Herbert, 1948-1950 (Box 12)
    - Gara, Larry, 1950-1955, undated (Box 12)
    - Gates, Paul W., 1947-1958, undated (Box 12)
    - Geer, Russel M., 1947-1953 (Box 12)
    - General Education Board, 1944-1945, undated (Box 12)
    - George, John, 1927-1929 (Box 12)
    - Gewehr, W. M., 1947-1949 (Box 12)
    - Geyl, Pieter, 1950-1951 (Box 12)
    - Giddens, Paul H., 1948-1958 (Box 12)
    - Gilliam, W. D., Jr., 1947-1956 (Box 12)
    - Gilmore, Harlan W., 1947-1949 (Box 12)
    - Gingerich, Melvin, 1944-1954 (Box 13)
    - Ginn, Mildred, 1931-1934, undated (Box 13)
    - Gipson, Lawrence, 1942-1946, undated (Box 13)
    - Giraud, Marcel, 1947-1953 (Box 13)
    - Glover, William H., 1945-1951 (Box 13)
    - Glunt, James D., 1927-1951, undated (Box 13)
    - Goldman, Eric, 1948-1957 (Box 13)
    - Goldsmith, A. O., 1953 (Box 13)
    - Goddykoontz, Colin B., 1948-1953 (Box 13)
    - Govan, Tom, 1947-1952 (Box 13)
    - Grady, James F., 1958-1960, undated (Box 13)
    - Grant, Charles S., 1951-1953, undated (Box 13)
    - Grantham, Dewey W., Jr., 1951-1959 (Box 13)
    - Green, E.R.R., 1951-1952 (Box 13)
    - Green, Fletcher M., 1944-1958, undated (Box 13)
    - Greenfield, Kent Roberts, 1944-1948, undated (Box 13)
    - Greever, William S., 1947-1957, undated (Box 13)
    - Gregory, James F., 1946-1952 (Box 13)
    - Gressley, Gene M., 1962-1965 (Box 13)
    - Griffin, Russell A., 1949-1950, undated (Box 13)
    - Griffith, William J., 1947-1952, undated (Box 13)
    - Grimes, Alan P., 1949 (Box 13)
    - Grodinsky, Julius, 1946-1949, undated (Box 13)
    - Gunderson, Robert, 1950-1951 (Box 13)
    - Hac-Hy, 1932-1961, undated, (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Hacker, Louis M., 1947-1948 (Box 14)
    - Hahn, Mannel, 1947-1948 (Box 14)
    - Haines, George IV, 1947-1949, undated (Box 14)
    - Haines, Lewis F., 1955 (Box 14)
    - Haines, Paul, 1953, undated (Box 14)
    - Hamer, Philip M., 1945-1947 (Box 14)
    - Hamilton, Holman, 1948-1957, undated (Box 14)
    - Hamilton, William B., 1945-1960 (Box 14)
    - Handlin, Oscar, 1948-1962 (Box 14)
    - Hanna, A. J., 1944-1952 (Box 14)
    - Hansen, Millard W., 1948, undated (Box 14)
    - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc., 1947-1952 (Box 14)
    - Harding, H. F., 1947-1949, undated (Box 14)
    - Harkness, Albert, Jr., 1948-1950 (Box 14)
    - Harper, Norman D., 1951-1952, undated (Box 14)
    - Harper and Brothers, 1946-1958 (Box 14)
    - Harris, Rufus C., 1946-1953, undated (Box 14)
    - Hartman, William, 1952-1953 (Box 14)
    - Harvard University Press, 1926-1948, undated (Box 14)
    - Hatcher, William H., 1949 (Box 14)
    - Hawgood, John A., 1950-1958, undated (Box 14)
    - Hay, T. R., 1947-1949 (Box 14)
    - Hayes Foundation, 1945-1946, undated (Box 14)
    - Hayes Memorial, 1941-1942 (Box 14)
    - Hayter, Earl W., 1945-1947, undated (Box 14)
    - Heald, Morrell, 1952 (Box 14)
    - Hedges, James B., 1948-1954 (Box 14)
    - Heffernan, Capt. John B., 1947-1953 (Box 14)
    - Heflin, Frank, 1947-1948 (Box 14)
    - Heilman, Robert B., 1947, 1960 (Box 14)
    - Helfman, Harold M., 1949-1953 (Box 14)
    - Helmes, Winifred G., 1949-1951 (Box 14)
    - Henderickson, Walter B., 1949-1951, undated (Box 15)
    - Henry Holt and Company, 1947-1953 (Box 15)
    - Herrington, George S., 1951 (Box 15)
    - Hesseltine, W. B., 1947-1960, undated (Box 15)
    - Hicks, John D., 1948-1955 (Box 15)
    - Hidy, R. W., 1949-1957 (Box 15)
    - Higginbotham, S. W., 1945-1963 (Box 15)
    - Higham, John, 1948-1952, undated (Box 15)
    - Hintz, Carl W., 1954-1959 (Box 15)
    - Historical News and Comments Section Proposed Reorganization, 1947 (Box 15)
    - Historical Society of Montana, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1941-1942 (Box 15)
    - Hobbs, William H., 1950, undated (Box 15)
    - Hodder, F. H., 1923-1930, undated (Box 15)
    - Hogan, William R., 1946-1955, undated (Box 15)
    - Hogue, Arthur R., 1949, undated (Box 15)
    - Holbrook, Leona, 1948 (Box 15)
    - Hollon, Gene, 1946-1950 (Box 15)
    - Holt, W. Stull, 1947-1954, undated (Box 15)
    - Hoole, W. Stanley, 1944-1957, undated (Box 15)
    - Horten, John T., 1947-1949 (Box 15)
    - Hostetter, R. J., 1948-1949 (Box 15)
    - House, Albert V., Jr., 1946-1963, undated (Box 15)
    - Howard, Harry N., 1947 (Box 15)
    - Howard, L. V., 1946-1953 (Box 15)
    - Howard, Robert W., 1958 (Box 15)
    - Howe, George F., 1947-1953, undated (Box 15)
    - Hubbard, John R., 1949-1952 (Box 15)
    - Hubbell, Jay B., 1947-1954 (Box 15)
    - Huntington, Samuel P., 1948-1950 (Box 15)
    - Huston, James A., 1946-1952 (Box 15)
    - Hutchinson, William T., 1944-1959 (Box 15)
    - Hyman, Harold M., 1950-1952, undated (Box 15)
    - Id-Ir, 1947-1953 (Box 16)
    - Iba, H. B., 1947-1949 (Box 16)
    - Indiana Historical Society, 1929-1958, undated (Box 16)
    - Interdepartmental Seminar, 1942-1948, undated (Box 16)
    - Ja-Ju, 1927-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)